Oh man, good afternoon everybody.
Just want to start off by saying man,
God is amazing. Uh
14 years of playing football, uh to come
to this moment,
uh I never thought I'd be in this
situation. I never thought I'd be here,
you know. Um, growing up playing the
game of football like 6 years old, I
always did it for the fun of it. Did it
for the love of it. Never cared about
what came with it just because, you
know, it was built in me a different
way. You know, um, just the way it
brings joy to people life, the way I can
impact people lives. And, you know, um,
my 14 career, 14 year career was a
journey. Uh, it was a long road to get
here.
uh you know starting at Liberty City
Optimus going to Miami Northwestern and
then going to junior college is when I
didn't think I would get here just
because everything that I went through
there it was a a tough journey but there
you know I learned you know what it
takes you know to become you know
accountable and I learned you know that
you know a lot of people depend on you
and you know uh going to the University
of Nebraska. I kept that chip, kept that
same mindset and throughout every year
that I've been here,
I had that same mentality, you know, um
just have that chip on my shoulder and
every time I step on the field, I want
to prove myself right and all my
daughters wrong. And a lot of people in
this building, a lot of people, guys who
I see in my family help me continue that
dream, could help me continue that
process. And you know, I want to thank
everybody, you know, throughout, you
know, my journey, throughout my career
for, you know, pushing me and helping
me, you know, be the greatest I can be.
And,
uh,
man, to play at an organization, you
know, for this long and to, you know, to
get all the respect that I have from
everybody and, you know, from all my
peers and the lives that I touch, you
know, throughout my career. uh something
you can always dream of, you know. Um
I might get a little emotional cuz it's
always how I always get when I talk
about my parents.
I mean, everybody have parents, man. But
you understand how much they meant to
me.
Growing up where I grew up,
it ain't easy. It ain't easy. But they
found a way for me. And you don't
understand that until you get older,
until you have kids on your own and the
sacrifices they made for you. The things
they did for you.
It's just
thinking about my dad,
the sacrifices he made. He was never the
bread winner in our family, but for some
reason him and my mom made it work and
their relationship lasted for so long.
And when you saw, you know, how they was
compatible with each other and how they
made our lives easier and,
you know, we had one car, my mom took
the car to work and my dad used to take
me to practice on his handlebars, you
know, and on a bike we used to walk
sometimes. And you know, as a kid, you
like, dang, man. Like that walk was a
far walk. But you realize like
it's a sacrifice that you got to make to
help your sons, your kids' dreams come
true.
And and they did it.
And it was a point in my career, you
know, when my mom passed away in 2016.
I I didn't care about football no more.
I didn't want to play no more. I didn't
care for it anymore.
I wanted to, you know, just give it up
because honestly, I didn't have a reason
no more. I didn't have, you know, I was
doing everything I was doing because I
wanted to, you know, make all her dreams
come true cuz she helped me make my
dreams come true the day that I got
drafted. And, you know, from then on, I
was just working to make her life
easier, make her life happy. And the day
that she passed away, I thought I lost
it all. And luckily
uh I had friends, family,
uh you know, General was one of those
guys who, you know, came to my side
because he went through that early in
his his football journey and he you
know, helped me get through it. And then
my siblings, you know, I'm the youngest
of six. I mean, yeah, the youngest of
six. My other two sisters, they weren't
able to make it today. But my household,
the ones who I had in my household, man.
Um, I was the youngest and my oldest
brother, Maris, right here, my other
brother, Gerard, right there, and my
sister.
Oh man, they made my life so easy. And
like I said, man, like they protected
me. And they went all through the bad
things before it got to me. You know, my
oldest brother, he took all the beatings
from my daddy before it was my time. My
sister, she took the chewing out from my
mom and dad. And you know, my brother
right here, Gerard, he was more the
knucklehead, but you know, um, you know,
they kind of like took it easy on him a
little bit, but by the time they got to
me, they was old and tired, so I was
okay. But, um, n man, it was uh just an
incredible moment just growing up in a
house of people who just support you and
who love you and generally wants to see
you live out your dreams and, you know,
every big moment. That's why I always
have them here with me because, you
know, they was with me every step of the
way. And,
you know, my little league coaches,
uh, all those guys, um, my high school
coaches, my college coaches, you know,
everybody who played a huge part in in
my career, man, I just want to salute
you and I want to take my hat off for
you guys and let them know that I love
them dearly. And um you know, coach BA
and coach Bose, it was another point in
my career where you know, it was another
it was a coaching change coming and you
know, I thought it might be you know, a
change of the guard, you know, a clean
house situation, but Jason, those guys
reached out to me and told me like,
"Nah, man. We want you to be a part of
this and it's going to turn around and
we going to basically do it for you."
And when they said that, I'm like, "Hey,
for me, man, y'all want me to be a part
of this?" I'm like, "I don't Oh, you
know, uh, it's a whole new scheme. You
know, Coach B coming with a 34 system. I
only I played in a 4-3 my whole career.
I don't know how to adjust to that. And,
uh, they told me, you know, you going to
have fun. Trust me, you're going to love
it. And I just remember telling B the
first meeting. Yeah. Yeah. This is what
I like to do right here. I appreciate
that. I think I'm going to have fun in
this. And I told him, man, you know, you
those guys like help me
uh have fun with the game again. And and
it shows every time I'm out there on the
field. You know, I see some of the guys,
some of my old teammates are here right
now. I hope you guys know that. Man, I
greatly appreciate you guys and you guys
brought joy to me every time I stepped
on the field to be able to live up to
not only my standards, but the standards
you guys hold me to. And that's why I
really love y'all boys held me
accountable from from the jump. And
that's something that I really
appreciate about you guys. Uh, you know,
Tandy held me accountable since I first
condition test with coach Sam, I mean,
with coach uh coach. And you know how
that was, you know. Um it was uh that
was crazy, but that's a story for
another time. But um you know, I thank
those guys too, man. Uh Mark Dominic, uh
Greg Shiano, and obviously the the
Glazer family. You guys help a kid from
Miami Dreams come true. And uh I thank
you guys big time for that. And um it's
greatly appreciated. My family
appreciate you guys. And you know, like
I always say, man, it comes from the
bottom of my heart. I can't thank you
guys enough. And you know uh with all
that being said uh my 14 year career has
come to an end and I feel it's time to
you know move on and you know find a
different path in life mainly uh being a
dad to that amazing little girl over
there
changed my life so much.
You know, people always talk about like,
man, you need to have a daughter. You
need to have a daughter. You never
understand. I'm like, why do you want me
to have a daughter so bad? And I'm like,
everybody, you know, being a masculine
man, you want to have a son. Like, I
want a son so he could, you know, follow
my footsteps and do, you know, so I can
help him become a man. But
I knew having a girl helped me become a
man, help me understand what's important
in life. and
she definitely does that daily and I'm
thankful. I'm sure she'll understand
right now, but when she look back,
she'll see, you know, um it's just an
incredible journey. is an incredible
time in my life to be able to just be
able to raise her to be an incredible
young woman and be the be the best
person in the world and be kind, be
generous, be loving and be caring to
people who you come across and I see it
in already and I just hope that you know
I continue to do that and always man
thank you guys so much. Love the crew
forever, the fans. You guys are amazing.
You guys are incredible. You guys always
was my motivation to uh wake me up in
the morning to keep me going to be able
to, you know, play the game at a high
level, you know, for this long. You guys
was a part of that. And I thank you guys
dearly for that, too, as well. And, you
know, trust me, this thing around here
is going to continue to get better,
continue to get greater. And, you know,
um, uh, end of the day, I will always be
a Buccaneer. As always, it's Bucks for
life.
Thank you, Levante. We're going to go
ahead and open it up to questions now.
Media, please raise your hands and a
microphone will be extended.
>> Levante JP Peterson Fanstream Sports
Tampa Bay. Congratulations on an amazing
career. Um, how important is it to make
it into the Hall of Fame for you?
Obviously, you have the numbers. What do
you think that process is going to be
like for you?
>> Oh, man. Uh, I don't know how the Hall
of Fame work or anything like that, but
I know the pro process will be, you
know, probably long, you know. Um, I
know a lot of accolades that comes into,
you know, deciding, you know, what you
do to get into the Hall of Fame and
stuff like that. But, you know, I never
been the one to brag and boast, but you
know, I let all my player stuff do the
talking. And, you know, to add to that,
my numbers do the talking. So, um, when
I'm out on the field, I make an impact
anyway I can. And I hope, you know,
someday they do decide, they do decide
to vote me in, they can see that. But,
it's something that I it was never
nothing that I strive for, you know. Uh,
like I said, man, um, I generally love
the game of football and, you know,
whatever comes with it just came with
it. But if that's a part of it, I
definitely would say accept the smiling.
>> Congratulations, Levante. Thanks, Scott.
Reynolds Peter report.
>> Your last game was Leventage or was
vintage Levante. David, I know you
battled a knee injury last year and you
went through a lot of pain
>> to have to play, but to go out with the
win
>> with a takeaway, which is the calling
card of your career
>> and um you know and and to to have that
type of game
>> tying Derek Brooks for the all-time
franchise tackle record.
>> What is your reflection on that game?
>> Oh, it was a fun game to be a part of.
just was was at stake, you know, uh the
tackle record that was in the back of my
mind obviously and you know what could
have happened in the future, you know.
Um unfortunately, you know, outside of
that things didn't happen didn't go the
way we go that the way we wanted to go.
But my whole thing was to play my heart
out, you know, no matter what. Uh that
just my mo, you know, every time I'm out
on the field, you know, these guys in
here know how I am. Uh they count on me
to be my best. you know, it's just a a
standard that they hold me to and it's a
standard that I hold myself to. And you
know, I each time I prepare, I try to
prepare that I'm at my best. Um that,
you know, I'm play my best uh full
effort. And I never want those guys to
question, you know, whether I play my
best or not. Uh whether it's from my
very first game or from my very last
game, you know, always wanted to go out
the same way I came in. That's, you
know, just trying to be the best on the
field.
>> Hey, Levante. Greg Almond from Fox
Sports over here on your left. Um, we
got you the night of that last game and
got to talk to you that night and
certainly knew that this was on your
mind and a possibility then, but just
want to ask you how tough a decision
this was for you
>> and then what were the things that
ultimately made this decision and gave
you the peace to know this is the right
time to to step away?
>> Yeah, it was extremely tough. Obviously,
I was going back and forth with it for a
very long time. Um but you know luckily
you know um I have nobody in my on my
camp that you know kind of pressure me
and to make the decisions you know um
from both sides family and the
organization you know gave me a little
time to like just think things through
and you know just figure out you know
what I want to do what I genuinely want
to want to do and I just felt it was
time you know um like I said man I I
never dreamed of you know playing 14
years in the NFL. I never, you know,
dreamed of playing 14 years in one
organization. Um, and, you know, um,
it's it's been an incredible journey and
I feel like it's just it was just time
for me to just, you know, move on and
let the the next generation, you know,
take over and, you know, I'm just, uh,
move on and find uh, my next passion, my
next endeavor. Um,
when, you know, when I got in the
league, you know, this is all I was
focused on was just football, football,
football. And it got to a point where
just like, you know, and people used to
ask me, "Man, what's your hobby? What's
your hobby?" I said, "I only got one
hobby. It's play football." And, you
know, that's something that kind of like
dawned on me, too. Like, you know, I
just got to figure out, you know, my
life, my own path, and, you know, kind
of go from there.
>> Levante, Jenna Lane, ESPN over here.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you. you talked about your mom and
I I didn't realize um just how um that
you got to a point where you didn't know
if you even wanted to play football
anymore after she passed away. Uh
because every time you walk in that
locker room,
>> you see her picture. It's the first
thing that many people see because it's
right there in your locker. What did
seeing her face every single day that
you would go to work? Like was that a
source of comfort for you, motivation?
What did that do for you? Yeah,
definitely source of comfort and
inspiration, you know. Um, you know, um
I always, you know, look at that picture
and and say to myself, you know, just
keep going, you know, uh keep striving,
keep making her proud. And, you know,
like you said, it's the first thing I
look at every time I look at my locker.
And, you know, that just what it brings,
you know, uh me to continue playing, me
continue to, you know, try to play this
game at a high level. I know I'm I'm
making her proud and all her sacrifices
and you know going none and void, you
know. Um it just she's one of those
people who always, you know, was
supportive, always was proud and you
know, I could always hear her saying
that's my baby. And even even as a grown
man calling me her baby, you know, uh
and we had that type of relationship,
you know, and I acted like a baby when I
was rhyming, too. So, uh um every time I
came home, uh first place I had to go
was to her house. You know, I remember
they were trying to do a surprise party
for me. My sister could tell you this.
They're trying to do a surprise party
before me had to have dinner and they
were trying to get me to go to the
restaurant. I'm like, "No, I got to go
to my mama house first. Like, I ain't
been to my mama house yet." She like,
"Boy, she going to be there. Just go to
the to the restaurant first." I like,
"No, I got to go to my mama house first.
What y'all talk about?" And come to find
out, she's done. And I'm surprised, too.
So, uh, that just how, you know, close a
relationship we had, man. Um, you know,
um, it was, uh, like that point, you
know, in my career, it just was, you
know, just tough to deal with, you know,
as anybody would go through just losing
a parent. But just how impactful she was
for me, how much she meant to me, you
know, it just was no point just to go
out there and just like not prove her
happy cuz that's who I wanted to do it
for. Uh but luckily you know my dad at
the time and my family was kind of like
still I had my motivation had still
pushing me and uh I just had to find a
different passion a different motivation
and I was able to find it and it was for
those guys I just see how proud of them
proud of me they were too as well. So I
was like yeah I still got to I still got
to keep doing this man. I still got
people rooting for me. I still got
people back home who want to see me
succeed. So you know uh I still got to
have that drive.
Can you hear me? Okay. Yeah. Uh Rick
Stout, Tampa Bay Times. Um I know you've
been retired for all of 21 minutes. Um
what have you thought about uh when you
think about your future? Not that you
need to work right away, but uh just,
you know, will you do you think you'll
want to do something in sports and
football? Is there anything that's come
to your mind during this time when you
were reflective about about not playing?
>> Yeah, different things came across my
mind. Like I said, man, I love the game.
I still want to be a part of the game. I
still want to, you know, do do things as
a part of the game. Uh maybe it's
broadcasting, maybe it's getting into
scouting, maybe it's coaching. I don't
know for sure yet, but it's some things
that I may venture into. Um the good
Lord is has blessed me, man, to be able
to take a little time off to be able to
think about that. So, I'm not uh I'm not
really, you know, tripping about that,
but I'm definitely going to, you know,
unwind a little bit, man. I've been
playing football since I was 6 years
old. 6 years old and never took a year
off. never took a year off, you know.
So, it was a so basically 30 years of
playing football. So, I think I uh
almost a little self a little time to
chill and kind of like enjoy life a
little bit.
>> Hey, Levante, congratulations on a
legendary career. JC Allen, uh I just
want to ask you 14 years, there's a lot
of memories, a lot of moments that I'm
sure come to your mind, not counting the
Super Bowl. What are some of those
moments when you look back and think of
that were impact imp impactful for your
career? Oh man. Uh, obviously,
uh,
I think I think the main thing for real,
man, just going through those tough
seasons, you know, building my
character, you know, building my
passion, you know, building my drive,
you know, and understanding, you know,
that it it means a lot to me, you know.
Um, uh, a lot of people going through
those time of f would quit, you know,
just turn into a-holes and, you know,
just fall off. But my drive, my passion
was different. You know, I like to say I
I'm built different, you know. Um, you
know, I always want to prove people
wrong. Like I going through those times,
I used to see all the message boards,
all the, you know, the the down talking,
all the the naysayers, all the, you
know, the people saying, you know, the
people with the the trash bags over
their heads and stuff like that. That
was my motivation. That was my drive.
And I think going through that right
there kind of like driven me to, you
know, play my hardest and kind of shut
people up and thank God I got a chance
to do that by winning the Super Bowl and
I'm going with that for a very long
time.
>> Congrats, Latte. Scott Smith, Fox 13
over here to your left. Um, I'm sure
you've talked with guys that have gone
through this and and contemplated their
own retirement and gone through that
part. What What are the aspects for you
individually that you think you're going
to miss the most? Oh man, you can look
around, man. I'm going to miss these
guys honestly. Uh the players, you know,
the coaches who I build a relationship
with, you know, the staff, you know,
everybody who's in here, you know, um
they in here for a reason, you know. Um
I I touched their lives in some type of
way and they touched mine. Um the
relationship we built over the years
with these people, man, is is
incredible, you know. Um that's just how
I always am, you I'm always, you know,
try to be kind. I always try to, you
know, put others feelings above mine.
And, you know, I just try to, you know,
impact people way impact people lives,
you know, just as much as they impact
mine. And, you know, I I don't look at
it just a job for them. You know what
I'm saying? It's it's really a real life
genuine relationship. And, you know,
when you see these people around, it
shows that they they're here to support
me. And it'll be the same thing the
opposite. I support them the same way,
you know. Uh some people are here I'm uh
I'm in contact with their kids life
outside of outside of football, outside
of the building, you know. Um I check up
on people, you know, from time to time.
Um I, you know, kind of like reach out
and see how their kids doing and stuff
like that, see how they doing, you know.
Um I get reminders about people's
birthdays to make sure I'm on point, you
know, to tell people happy birthday who
I'm close with. So, you know, uh
everybody is here in here for a reason.
And you know, uh, my dad used to always
say, man, like, you know, it don't takes
nothing to be kind to people. You never
know what people is going through. And,
you know, that just something that I
live by. And, you know, I just remember
and it stuck to me. You know, I remember
he was in the hospital uh, going through
what he was going through and a nurse
came in and he just asked her like she
looked like she was like frustrated or
whatever. And I'm in there with him and
she's like like, "Hey, put a smile on
your face. You know, uh, you know,
everything going to be better.
Everything going to be great." And you
know, I'm I'm just listening to him
talking. And as she left out, I'm like,
"How could you do that? And you going
through everything you going through."
And he said just like this, "I don't
give a damn what I'm going through. I
just want to make sure everybody around
me all right." And you know that that
that right there just meant so much to
me. And that's what made him who we are
and the reason why why I love him so
much.
>> Levante, uh, congratulations. Rock
Riley, WDAE, Tampa Free Press. Why? When
so many players over a long career will
look to see, you know what, I played
here a long time. Let me just go see
what it's like, go try to play somewhere
else.
>> Why did you just play with one team, the
Buccaneers? And how much did it mean to
you to just finish your career as only a
Buccaneer?
>> Oh man, they didn't want to let me go.
No, I'm joking, man. But nah, for real,
man. It's just,
oh, man, I I've built so many great
relationships here. Um,
a lot of people, like I just said,
touchdown, man. A lot of people who I
built relationships with here, you know,
kind of like, you know, impacted me in
different ways, you know, and um and I
couldn't just, you know, up a leaf, you
know, um when I start a battle, I want
to finish the battle. And, you know, I
always say, man, things get greater
later. And that indeed it did. And you
know, I'm thankful for, you know, the
Glazers, the Bucks, you know, Jason,
Coach B,
you know, uh, Coach Ba, you know, those
guys, you know, wanting me, you know, to
stick around and want me to be around to
help, you know, continue to mold this
program to what they want to be. And,
you know, and I think, you know, I was a
big part of getting the job done. Uh, as
you can see, we got guys locker room who
I mean this auditorium guys who Tristan
R, Anton Winfield, Takib bro. Uh, I
can't see nobody else but, uh, oh, dang,
Nelly,
you know, um, guys like that, man, who,
you know, kind of like the foundation of
what, you know, what it takes to be a
Buccaneer. And you know, guys who I
played with in the past, you know,
Donnie Gerald, you know, those guys JP
who's not here, you know, I talked to
him before we got here. Um, those guys
are, you know, people who I want to be
around, people who I want to, you know,
you know, build with, people who I want
to win with. And, uh, those guys could
tell you out their mouth, man, I I'll do
anything for them. And
you know it's just something about
obviously you know just something about
just sticking with what you starting
with and you know it takes you a long
way and that just something that you
know like I said man and something that
I never dreamed of it ended up happening
but I represent it with pride.
>> Levante all the way in the back here
Sean Barry Fox 13. I I'm curious those
who watched the documentary, they saw
and learned that anytime the Bucks bring
in a new player, either the draft or
free agency, they have to pass criteria
that
>> kind of define you and your silhouettes,
they, you know, decorate the the meeting
rooms all over this building. So, though
you won't be in this building anymore,
to know that your legacy and your
criteria still will be, what is that
like for you?
>> It's incredible, man. Like I said, you
look around, you see it. You see the
guys who we got, you know, the dolls
that we got, guys who I, you know, take
the field with any day. You know, I
won't mind walking through a dark alley
with those guys, you know, regardless,
you know. Um, it's just, but it's
incredible. You know, I found that out,
you know, a couple years ago when I was
doing my signing and uh when Jason
talked about it, it just kind of caught
me off guard. I'm like, you know what?
Like that's what I go by, you know. So,
you know, that kind of like made me
straighten up even more like, dang, I
got to, you know, kind of like walk on
eggshells around here now. But, uh, but
no, man, it's just, you know, it that's
goes to show, you know, what this
organization, you know, what the future
holds for the organization, you know,
uh, winning football, you know, uh,
underdog mentality, you know, go out
there and every game play like it's your
last. And you got guys in here who who's
going to do that. And I know that for a
fact because, you know, if you didn't
have those guys, you know, I wouldn't
be, you know, preparing to retire. I
just know this organization is going to
be in a great place and I know guys, you
know, around going to be able to, you
know, lead this this organization to the
promised land.
Levante Jenna again. Um I asked you a
couple years ago
>> what it would mean for you to be in the
Ring of Honor and at the time you said
it hadn't even registered
>> uh that you could potentially join those
greats.
>> What about now? What would it mean for
you?
>> Amazing. It'll be great, guys. It' be uh
it' be great to be in that uh like you
said, man. Like now, you know, football
is it, you I got a chance to kind of
like just reflect and think about, you
know, the things though that I may have,
you know, accomplished, may people may
see that's that's deemed successful
while playing football. So, um, I think
it's a a good resume. I would say I
think it's a solid resume and I think,
uh, if the Glazers will have me, I would
gladly accept.
Any other questions?
Levante, when people mention your name,
your legacy, what do you hope is said
about you?
>> Oh man, you know, um I get this question
a lot, but I'll be trying to find the
right words to say for it because it it
it means so much. just like a a really
really real question but
it's a it's a honestly a easy answer you
know just when I look around you know
my legacy I would say touched a lot of
people in a good way in a positive way.
Um, I felt as though like when I came in
this league, um, when I came to this
organization, I wanted to be the best
football player I can be. It's just best
football player I could be. But it
turned out the main thing was just being
the best person I could be. Uh,
and you know, like I said, man, I built
so many friendships with so many people
in here. And you know, um, that's
something that I, you know, kind of like
in there I'm really, really happy about.
You know, um, I know for a fact once I
leave this building, like there's nobody
in here that can't, you know, call my
phone and we can talk and we can talk
anytime. And that's something that I'm
most proud of, you know, besides the
football side. And, you know, um, I feel
like, you know, the football stuff
speaks for itself. But for me to
actually like come in the organization,
you know, be here for 14 years, for them
to accept me, accept my family, and for
them to be able to, you know, accept me
as not only not look at me as this
football player, but look at me as a
friend. That's the thing that I'm, you
know, I'm most proud of, you know, and
from for everybody in here, you know,
like I always say, man, I'm so thankful
y'all. Y'all gave me a reason to come in
this building and smile and be able to
be happy. Y'all know every time I come
here, I was happy to be here, you know.
Um, happy to throw jokes around with you
guys, happy to, you know, give you guys
a hard time sometimes, but at the end of
the day, it was all out of love, you
know. Um, from the training staff to the
strength staff to
uh to the the the the ticket staff, from
the the grounds people, from the the
front office side to especially the
media side. y'all know how I am with
y'all. But um from the weight room
staff, from you know, everybody, man,
the the film crew, the equipment staff,
like everybody played a pivotal role in
my life. And I'm definitely definitely,
you know, thankful and grateful for
y'all because y'all are such great
people. And I love being around great
people and y'all make me a great person.
I'm thankful for that. Appreciate it.